we are creating a global tech
cooperative what we are in the sector of
is technology how it is run is as a
cooperative which means it has to be run
as a democracy one-person one-vote there
can be some caveats to that as in
workers might get two votes one is a
member and one is an employee but it'll
be something we decide together you
definitely don't have one person because
there are majority shareholder there
won't be majority short merge area
majority shareholders you don't have one
person retain 51% of the vote you don't
have one person have ten times the vote
as somebody else even if there's ways to
game the system it's not going to be
folds of magnitude that currently exists
in our democracies or if you have money
and you have power you get to decide who
is up on the ticket and therefore that's
a lot more power than getting to give
your one vote so how do we make sure if
we are a democracy a democratic
corporation a cooperative that we aren't
run like what how we see our country is
being run with very few people in power
and they retain the power because we
don't have the media's owned by them the
they kind of get to run the the message
of what it takes to be in office and so
we're not electing scientists right
because we need economists and business
people political science majors to be to
be in office they are currently able to
very easily run on a platform get
elected and go back on a platform with
no repercussions besides maybe not
getting elected again in four years and
with a four-year term
they know our we have very little memory
they know they can go back and promises
and still probably get elected
especially they go back at the beginning
they know that well there's nothing they
can do for four years and that also
doesn't help us move our countries
forward because someone put something
into place for four years the next
person has to roll it back and put their
thing into place for four years it's
both too long to be a real democracy and
too short to be effective
we are going to create a system that the
people who've put those people in power
the voters retain their power what that
looks like is you delegate your vote to
somebody once a year there's an election
and that just means the top people with
delegated votes at midnight on this day
get to be on the board of directors the
top 10 people let's say now those 10
people don't have equal power at the
table we get equal voice we get to talk
and say how they feel they got to help
in the making of the decision but when
it comes time to vote their power is
reflective of how many members have
delegated their vote to them so if you
put a Board of Directors around that
table and they start acting in in their
self-interest in their friends
self-interest to make a profit instead
of to make purpose for us we transfer
our boat to somebody else and as we the
people who have put them in power don't
understand what's going on and it's too
complex we need to make the tools in
place to make it less complex to give us
access to that information once the
technology has caught up once we have
the technology people will be able to
vote directly on the issues themselves
but many of us will still want to
delegate are about to somebody else
because we don't want to attend every
meeting 10 million people attending a
weekly board meeting or whatever we
decide is the is the time in between
meetings is not that's millions of hours
spent watching meeting instead of if
that's not what you want to do and you'd
rather delegate your vote to somebody
who has expertise in that area yes let's
do that
we don't need to have a million people
making a decision but we do need a
million power people to empower a small
group of people without that small group
of people having supreme power having
power that we can't take back
even if it's only for a year or four
years so liquid democracy is just that
it's fluid democracy it's been able to
transfer your vote from one person to
another in between elections so the same
ten people in this example will be on
the board but your power around that
board could be from zero to a hundred
percent if you have a hundred percent of
the vote that's very unlikely
especially with a lot of members but you
if you have 51 percent of the vote which
isn't necessarily gonna be that unlikely
what you say your vision is what gets
moved forward people like yes that's
what we want to do and they give you
your vote you have you've been empowered
by it as soon as it gets to your head
and you're working in your own
self-interest and not theirs if your
self-interest is their self-interest
we're golden
but if your self-interest is not in the
members self-interest
they're gonna take their vote back from
you it's designed so that people can not
have concentrated power and retain it
while doing shitty shitty things also
probably shouldn't say this but when we
create a company that runs with liquid
democracy and we can see that millions
of us can come together and have an
effective conversation still move
forward we are not gonna stand for the
current democracies that we have when we
have a system to understand what's
happening on those meetings so we can
vote directly and the technology to vote
directly we are not going to stand for
what is happening in our current
democracies bringing the demands better
and we're gonna have the tools to create
better thanks please like and subscribe
I'll see you tomorrow